Steve Maciaszek

Cupertino, CA (650) 793-8244 stevemaciaszek@comcast.net

Overview

10+ years of development experience. Well-versed and comfortable in all stages of the software development life cycle. Strong focus on the front-end, comfortable on the back-end, and have had many successful implementations, both large and small.

Technical Summary

React, Angular, Vue, Node, jQuery, PHP, Wordpress, React Native, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Professional Experience

Web Developer

Druva. Sunnyvale, CA 10/2018 – 3/2019

Developer for druva.com. With a team of developers and product marketers, worked on a redesign and rebrand of their current website and associated properties. Used Wordpress framework to build all site components and landing pages in effort streamline productivity and allow the product marketing team to edit site pages.

Software Developer, contract

Cupertino, CA 2015 - 2019

Worked as Software Developer for various companies building out and enhancing their web and mobile applications.

- Used Angular and React to create applications for both web and mobile. Used React for the logical implementation part of the client side and Node/Express, for the back-end.
- Implemented key features within the discussions.apple.com. Developed an internal dashboard using Angular to streamline communication and efficiency for the internal customer support team in increase productivity.
- Developed and managed rich media advertising campaigns across desktop, mobile, and tablet on yahoo.com. Used HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Adobe Edge to execute each project.

 Companies that I worked with in this period: Apple - Mindsource, Apple - Hogarth Worldwide, Apple - Hero Digital, SAP - Mindlance, Yahoo - Staffing Headquarters.

UI Developer

*eH*ealth. Mountain View, CA 10/2012 – 12/2014

Successfully built-out and enhanced a number of eHealth web properties using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, including the corporate website, the current Resource Center, Medicare, and Affordable Care Act site.

- Lead Engineer for the website redesign, beginning with prototyping, and moving all the way to implementation of specific pages and components.
- Developed with a team, a set of consumer price index visualizations using HighCharts, Google Charts and D3 to allow users to track and analyze health insurance savings and to visualize future health plan offerings and savings.
- Worked as the Team Lead Developer on the front-end for the Affordable Care Act application using Node, Backbone, MongoDB.
- Developed a user Resource Center built with WordPress to assist users with their current health offerings and to boost overall retention.

Web Software Developer/System Admin, contract

Mountain View, CA 2007 - 2012

Worked with multiple clients to build-out and expand their web presence and software development needs. Collaborated with both large and small teams focused on project-based site maintenance. Comfortable communicating and working with remote individuals.

In additional to software web development, provided duties as a Systems Administrator and Dev-Ops engineer for Windows, Mac, and Linux, both client and server, for Piczo, Uptake, and Corporative Visions.

Web Developer/UI Prototyper

IMVU. Mountain View CA 10/2011 - 4/2012

As the Lead UI Developer, was tasked to prototype new features for all portions of the new site redesign.

- Worked seamlessly with the UI Design team to develop prototypes, new features, and functionality to build pieces of the new application. Developed user-interface elements in HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Conducted daily user tests to refine the prototype to enhance the products based on user-feedback, then modified code for efficiency and customer satisfaction.

Sr. Web Developer

Uptake. Palo Alto, CA 3/2011 - 10/2011

As a Senior Developer, successfully managed a full website redesign for a leading travel recommendations website. Worked comfortably in an agile environment that also included expanding and enhancing a robust Ruby on Rails application.

Sr. UI Developer

Apple. Cupertino, CA 11/2009 – 3/2011

As a developer for the Apple Online Store, built out the pages, modules, and components and also participated in numerous new product introductions.

- Developed landing pages, store pages, modules, and components for store.apple.com.
- Fixed localization issues with pages and modules, as well as, related CMS tasks.
- Handled site-wide bug fixes and enhancements for both desktop and mobile platforms.

UI Developer

Ooma. Palo Alto, CA 3/2008 – 11/2008

As the on-site Lead Developer, was responsible for the Ooma web application, which included providing guidance for diverse and remote teams to keep the teams streamlined, on schedule, and within budget. This was developed using dynamic PHP pages, while adhering to strict HTML and CSS compliance standards.

Founder/Web Developer

Piczo. San Francisco, CA 1/2002 - 12/2007

Founding team member (employee #2) for Piczo, which was a social sharing and website builder.

- Took the lead development role for the front-end user interface for this on-line site builder and social networking site for teenagers worldwide, garnering over 2.5 billion page views and 12 million unique visitors a month.
- Worked with investors to garner 5th Round Series D funding in addition to managing/building the Engineering Development team, securing office space, and managing the logistics of running an office.

Web Programmer

The Dialog Corporation. Mountain View, CA 1/2001 - 12/2002

As a Cold Fusion programmer, developed core sections of the company-wide Intranet to stream-line company processes and enhance worker-productivity.

Education

CSU, Chico. Bachelor of Arts, Instructional Technology.